A new hero finds his roar!
The Lion Guard: Return of the Roar is a family, tv movie,
animation film directed by Howy Parkins.
Set in the African savannah, the film follows Kion as he
assembles the members of the 'Lion Guard'.
Throughout the film, the diverse team of young animals will learn how to utilize each of their unique abilities to solve problems and accomplish tasks to
maintain balance within the Circle of Life, while also introducing viewers to the vast array of animals that populate the prodigious African landscape.
Kion (voice), played by Max Charles.
Bunga (voice), played by Joshua Rush.
Zuri (voice), played by Madison Pettis.
Janja (voice), played by Andrew Kishino.
Cheezi (voice), played by Vargus Mason.
Simba (voice), played by Rob Lowe.
The Lion Guard is an American animated children's television series developed by
Ford Riley and based on Disney Animation's 1994 film The Lion King.
The series was first broadcast with a television film titled The Lion Guard: Return of the Roar on Disney
Channel on November 22, 2015, and began airing as a TV series on January 15, 2016, on Disney Junior.
It is the second television series based on The Lion King
following The Lion King's Timon & Pumbaa (1995–1999).
The first two seasons take place within the time-gap in the
1998 film The Lion King II: Simba's Pride.
The majority of the third and final season takes place in parallel with the film's
second act, with the final two episodes serving as an epilogue to the film.
The second season premiered on July 7, 2017, followed by the third on August 3,
2019, with the series finale airing on November 3 the same year.